Arch Oboler Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
Arch Oboler Collection1916-1992 1936-1989
Oboler, Arch, 1909-1987
161.6 linear feet (363 boxes, approximately 127,050 items)
107 sound tape reels: analog, various speeds; 7 inch and 10 inch
124 sound cassettes: analog
4 sound discs: analog, 33 1/3 and 78 rpm; 10 inch and 12 inch
Recorded Sound Reference Center, Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Nearly the entirety of the prolific output of radio playwright and independent film maker Arch Oboler (1909-1987) in radio, motion pictures, television, theater, and print is contained in the Arch Oboler Collection. Featured are his radio plays from the 1930s and 1940s and the first three-dimensional feature film, Bwana Devil.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Green, Aaron G.--Correspondence.; Karloff, Boris, 1887-1969--Correspondence.; Kay, Jerry (Jerry J.), 1923-2002.; Leakey, L. S. B. (Louis Seymour Bazett), 1903-1972--Correspondence.; Masselink, Eugene, 1910-1962--Correspondence.; Oboler, Arch, 1909-1987--Archives.; Oboler, Arch, 1909-1987--Correspondence.; Oboler, Arch, 1909-1987--Homes and haunts--California--Malibu.; Oboler, Arch, 1909-1987.; Oboler, Arch, 1909-1987. Night of the auk.; Peters, William Wesley--Correspondence.; Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959--Correspondence.; Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959.; Wright, Iovanna Lloyd--Correspondence.; Wright, Olgivanna Lloyd--Correspondence.
Subjects
3-D films.; Horror radio programs--United States.; Motion picture authorship--United States.; Motion picture plays.; Paranormal fiction, American.; Radio authorship--United States.; Radio plays.; Radio programs.; Radio serials--United States.; Radio stories--United States.; Radio--Production and direction--United States.; Science fiction films--United States.; World War, 1939-1945--Drama.
Places
Malibu (Calif.)--Buildings, structures, etc.
Titles
Bwana devil (Motion picture); Lights out (Radio program)
Form/Genre
Adaptations.; Drafts (Documents); Financial records.; Horror radio programs.; Legal documents.; Letters (Correspondence); Photographs.; Promotional materials.; Radio propaganda.; Radio scripts.; Science fiction films.; Scripts (Documents); Sound recordings.; War radio programs.
Occupations
Architects and builders--United States.; Dramatists, American.; Motion picture producers and directors--United States.; Radio actors and actresses.; Radio producers and directors--United States.; Radio writers--United States.; Screenwriters--United States.
Administrative Information
Collection Acquisition
The Arch Oboler Collection was a 2003 gift to the Library of Congress from Guy Oboler, Janet Marilyn Reed, David Oboler, Marion S. Cox, Steven Oboler, Sylvia Kester Oboler, and the estate of Eleanor Oboler.
Additions
No further additions to the papers are expected.
Access Restrictions
The Arch Oboler Collection is open for research. Advance notice is required; contact a reference librarian in the Recorded Sound Reference Center, Library of Congress, Washington, DC, 20540-4690; (202) 707-7833.
Biographical Note
Best known as a writer and director of radio and movies, Arch Oboler was born in Chicago on December 7, 1909. He developed a keen interest in radio during its formative years in the 1920s and made his first big sale with a radio play entitled Futuristics. When Wyllis Cooper, creator of the radio series Lights Out, left that program in 1936, Oboler took the helm as writer and director. Using stream-of-consciousness dialogue and innovative sound effects in his broadcasts, he proved as adept with social consciousness, comedic, and dramatic topics as he did with the horror genre for which Lights Out is best remembered.
As the United States moved closer to entering World War II, Oboler’s radio drama, at times anti-war in tone, became increasingly focused on world events and alarmist about the rise of global totalitarianism. With direct American involvement in the conflict, the playwright gave his full support to the war effort with radio series such as Plays for Americans, To the President, and Everything for the Boys.
Oboler’s prolific radio play output numbered in the hundreds, and he worked with many notable actors and actresses of the 1930s and 1940s including Boris Karloff, James Cagney, Bette Davis, and Claude Rains. By war’s end, however, demand for his radio programs, and the popularity of radio in general, waned, as motion pictures and television became dominant forces in American entertainment. Oboler had moved to California in the late 1930s to seek his fortune and there he found work in film writing and then directing. Throughout his career, much of his work underwent constant revisions, and during and immediately after the war he adapted several of his radio plays for the movie screen. None were commercial successes, but Oboler remained determined to make the switch from radio to motion pictures. His subsequent six films, scripted and directed by him, were independent productions, covering such themes as post-nuclear war apocalypse (Five) and human sexuality (One Plus One).
Oboler’s greatest commercial achievement was the 1952 3-dimensional movie Bwana Devil, a dramatization of real-life events involving man-eating lions holding up railway construction in East Africa. The film spawned a short-lived 3-D movie craze and earned Oboler much money, but its release was not without legal battles over distribution rights and other matters. It was also during the making of Bwana Devil that a professional partnership was firmly forged between a one-time script girl named Jerry Kay (real name Geraldine Klancke) and Oboler. Bwana Devil, like many Oboler endeavors, had its challenges, and by proving her mettle in helping Oboler meet them, Jerry Kay became Oboler’s longtime and faithful personal assistant.
Following Bwana Devil, Oboler carried on in filmmaking and, with growing public nostalgia for old time radio programming, he rebroadcast and released on record and tape many of his early stories. Some of his radio dramas had been published in book form as anthologies during his heyday, and in later years he wrote numerous articles for magazines such as Reader’s Digest. He drafted thousands of pages of novel scripts but, with the exception of the horror thriller House on Fire, was unable to get them into print. A few forays into television, which during Oboler’s lifetime threatened both the motion picture industry and radio, brought him little gain. His major stage play effort, the 1956 Night of the Auk (about a manned spacecraft returning to an earth devastated by nuclear war) was a Broadway failure. True to Oboler’s revisionist formula, an adaptation was broadcast on public television in 1960.
Oboler married Eleanor Helfand in 1937 and they had four sons. In the 1940s he corresponded and became friends with noted architect Frank Lloyd Wright, whom Oboler greatly admired and about whom he wrote published articles and a proposed biographical television treatment. Wright designed a residence for the Obolers near Malibu, California. Only partially built, the completed portions, which incorporated stones from Oboler’s mineral collection, became Oboler’s beloved home. Located in the rugged Santa Monica Mountains, the home served as an effective budget movie set for his post-nuclear war film, Five.
By the time of his death on March 19, 1987, Arch Oboler, had left an indelible impression on American entertainment culture, working with and inspiring show business luminaries from the 1940s and 1950s as well as later stars such as Bill Cosby, one of whose comedy routines centered on the terrifying effects of listening to the radio play "Chicken Heart," an episode from Lights Out. Innovative and creative, Oboler was a highly sought-after and award-winning radio playwright at the height of his career. Though his commercial success diminished with radio’s decline in American life, he never wavered in turning out ideas and stories and became in the end an icon to those who remembered the Golden Age of Radio.
Scope and Content Note
Arch Oboler’s career as author, radio and stage playwright and director, and movie script writer and director spanned some sixty years, from the late 1920s to the 1980s. Included in his papers is his accumulation of correspondence, legal, business, and personal files, and manuscript and other materials related to his vast creative output in different media.
Almost all of the scripts from his radio programs in the 1930s and 1940s, including the Lights Out series, are preserved in multiple copies, some with handwritten annotated cues and notes. Amply documented in the papers are most of the films on which Oboler worked as writer, director, or producer, including his greatest commercial success, the 1952 3-D movie Bwana Devil. As is the case with other Oboler films, among the Bwana Devil documents are business and legal papers, promotional and production documents, and movie stills and photographs of filming.
Oboler met architect Frank Lloyd Wright in the early 1940s, but it was not until after World War II that the famous architect designed a house and other residential buildings for Oboler. Included in the papers is correspondence between Oboler and Wright, and documentation relating to construction and upkeep of the portions of Wright’s architectural designs which were actually used in residential construction for Oboler near Malibu, California, where Oboler lived until his death in 1987.
Oboler’s prolific creative output continued into the 1960s and beyond, when he made several feature films which are documented in the papers. He also wrote and published books, magazine articles, and short stories, and wrote, produced, and directed an unsuccessful Broadway play, the Night of the Auk. The papers describe the play’s development, production, and reception upon its New York opening and in later off-Broadway productions. Oboler characteristically employed story lines in different media (the Night of the Auk was also one of his infrequent television productions) and reworked earlier radio stories for proposed television and film treatment. Numerous book and short story manuscripts and television and film scripts with reworked and original plots are included in the Oboler papers, as are materials related to commercial LP record and cassette tape releases of some of his famous early radio plays.
Major correspondents include Bette Davis, Aaron Green (San Francisco architect), Boris Karloff, anthropologist Louis Leakey, Gene Masselink (an associate of Frank Lloyd Wright), William Wesley Peters (an associate of Frank Lloyd Wright), Frank Lloyd Wright, Olgivanna Lloyd Wright (Frank Lloyd Wright's wife), and Iovanna Lloyd Wright (the Wrights's daughter).
Collection Arrangement
The papers are arranged in 11 series:
Series 1: Correspondence, circa 1934-1987
Series 2: Film, circa 1925-1985
Series 3: Frank Lloyd Wright/Real Estate, 1940-1989
Series 4: Legal and Business Files, 1934-1991
Series 5: Manuscripts, 1920-1986
Series 6: Miscellaneous, 1932-1992
Series 7: Night of the Auk, 1946-1968
Series 8: Ranch Files, 1927-1977
Series 9: Scripts, 1933-1993 and undated
Series 10: Catalog File, 1941-1969
Series 11: Sound Recordings, 1938-1987 and undated
http://lccn.loc.gov/2011622952
Container List
- Series 1. Correspondence, circa 1934-1987, 13.3 linear feet (32 boxes)
  Among the Oboler papers are a number of folders originally labeled “Correspondence,” some of which date from Oboler’s radio career in the 1930s and 1940s. Of interest are letters to and from radio and film stars such as Boris Karloff and Bette Davis, fan mail to Oboler, and material related to Oboler’s Mutual Broadcasting System radio work in 1945. Correspondence from later dates is not as well organized and, characteristic of the “catch-all” nature of the Oboler papers, contains diverse materials on topics such as union membership, income taxes, travel, real estate, and product warranties and guarantees.
  Materials from the early period of his career are among the best organized files of the collection, retaining their original arrangement, alphabetical by subject (including, for example, radio program titles) or correspondent, and within folder chronological, reverse chronological, or alphabetical by correspondent.
  - Specific recipients and topics, 1936-1952
    - AFRA, 1941 January-November (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Approved contract forms, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Arch Oboler: paid bills, insurance receipts, etc., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Arnelo Affair, 1945 September-1947 July (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Art of Radio Writing," 1940 August (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Berke, Sam, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Black, Ivan, 1939 September-1949 December (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Blackett - Sample - Hummert, Inc., 1938 September-1941 March (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - Books, 1942 March (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Burr, Jane, 1939 September-1941 May (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Charities, 1940 January-1944 April (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Copyright material, 1939 September-1942 May (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Council for Democracy, 1941 September-1941 December (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Dean Witter & Company, 1941 March-June (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Draft business, 1941 March (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Earle, Harley, 1940 December (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - European trip, 1938 May-October (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Everyman's Theater scripts returned, 1938 April-1940 November (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Arch Oboler radio program, 1940-1941.
    - Everyman's Theater advance synopsis, circa 1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Free film, 1941-1943, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
    - Follow up folder (weekly), current material, 1940 September-1941 November (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Gang & Kopp, 1940 June-1951 February (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
    - Garbo affair, 1942 January-March (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Garden, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - General Amusement Corporation, Jimmy Parks, 1938 September-1941 November (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Gilmore, Max E., 1942 April (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Glassley, Chester, 1941 October-1952 May (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Immediate, 1940 January-1942 February (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Institute for Education by Radio, 12th and 13th, 1941 May-1946 June (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - J. Walter Thompson, Inc., 1937 January-1939 July (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Kastor, H.W. & Sons, 1937 April-1939 June (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Leland Hayward, Inc., 1939 February-1941 November (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943 and undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1936 June-1942 May (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Motion Picture Buyers Guide, 1940-1945 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Music, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Musicians Mutual Protective Association, 1940 October (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - NBC correspondence, 1939, 1937 December-1939 December (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - NBC correspondence, 1940, 1939 December-1940 December (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - NBC, Wally West, 1940 January-1941 February (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Other NBC correspondence, 1937 July-1941 November (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Procter & Gamble, 1940 November-1941 May (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Publicity, Plays for Americans, 1942 February-March (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Arch Oboler World War II radio series, 1942.
    - Radio editors, 1938 February-1946 June (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Radio Writers Guild, 1939 May-1947 December (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Ranch furniture, 1941 April-August (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Random House book, 1940 January-1942 May (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Read, Oliver: radio, 1940 April-September (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Red Cross, 1940 September-1941 October (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Red White & Blue (army), 1941 May-June (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Rutherhauff & Ryan, 1938 April-1941 September (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Services, 1946 November-1952 July (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Speech material, 1939 June-October (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Stocks, 1941 March-September (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Strange Holiday correspondence, 1944 January-1952 January (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Strange Morning correspondence, 1944 July-1945 February (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Treasury show, 1941, 1941 June-October (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 20th Century Fox, 1941 April-October (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Union Bank & Trust Co., 1941 September-November (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - University correspondence, 1938 November-December, 1941 January-August (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Variety, 1938 May-1941 August (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Weston, George, His First Million Women, 1941 October-November (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - William Morris Agency, 1937 April-1941 September (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - William Targ (book), 1940 March-1941 December (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence arranged alphabetically, 1937-1942
    - A to G, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - G to M, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - N to T, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - T to Z, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - A, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - B, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - C, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - D, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - F, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - G, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - H, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - J, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - K, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - L, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - M, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - N, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - O-P, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - R, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - S, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - T, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - V, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - W, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - A, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - B, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - C, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - D, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - E, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - F, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - G, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - H, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - J, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - K, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - L, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - M, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - N, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - O-P, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - R, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - S, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - T, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - V, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - W, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - A, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - B, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - C, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - D, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - E, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - F, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - G, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - H, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - I, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - J, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - K, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - L, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - M, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - N-O, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - P, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - R, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - S, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - T, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - V, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - W, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - XYZ, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - B, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - C, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - D, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - E, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - F, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - G, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - H, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - J, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - K, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - L, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - M, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - N, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - O, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - P, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - R, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - S, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - T, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - V, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - W, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - XYZ, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - A, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - B, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - C, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - D, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - E, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - F, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - G, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - H, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - I-J, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - K, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - L, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - M, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - N, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - O, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - P-Q, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - R, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - S, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - T, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - U-V, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - W, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - XYZ, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence by subject, chiefly early to mid 1940s, 1936-1946
    - A, miscellaneous, 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Actors, N to Z, 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Auditions, 1944, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - B, miscellaneous, 1941-1944 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - BBC (V-E Day), 1944 October-December (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Biow, 1944 March-June (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Black, Ivan, 1942 June-1944 December (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Bright Weapon, 1944 June-December (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - C, miscellaneous, 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Chinese Gong, business correspondence, 1944 March-April (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Christmas lists, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Cyzio, 1941, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - D, miscellaneous, 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Draft board, 1942-1945 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Dryer, Sherman, 1942 July-August (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - E, miscellaneous, 1942 May-November (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Elgin Christmas program, Bette Davis, 1942 December (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Everything for the Boys material, 1941-1945 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - F, miscellaneous, 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Fan mail, answered, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Four for the Fifth and Sixth, 1944 May-December (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Free World Theatre: advance schedules, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Free World Theatre: book, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Free World Theatre: fan mail, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Free World Theatre: general correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Free World Theatre: manuscripts submitted, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Free World Theatre: minutes of meetings, 1943 April-June (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Free World Theatre: original statements and correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 10, Folder 9-10)
    - Free World Theatre: publicity, 1942 December-1943 June (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Free World Theatre: requests for scripts, 1944 July-August (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Free World Theatre: complete script set, 1943 February-June (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
    - G, miscellaneous, 1942-1944 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Gang, Kopp & Tyre, attorneys, 1942 August-1944 July (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Gangway for Tomorrow: general correspondence, 1943 April-1944 February (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - H, miscellaneous, 1942-1944 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "High Command," circa 1945 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      An episode of Four for the Fifth, a World War II radio drama.
    - Holiday correspondence, 1943 November-1944 January (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - I, miscellaneous, 1942 February-1944 December (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Indians, 1943 July-August (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Institute for Education by Radio, 1942 May-1944 October (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Insurance, 1941-1944 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - J, miscellaneous, 1942-1944 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - K, miscellaneous, 1942-1944 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Kathleen Goddard, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - L, miscellaneous, 1942-1944 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Lengel, article, 1944 August-November (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Lights Out: auditions, circa 1942 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Lights Out: business and personal correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
    - Lights Out: miscellaneous schedules, synopses, etc., 1936-1937, 1942-1943 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - "Lights Out: requests for scripts or permission to re-broadcast, 1942 December-1944 September (Box 12, Folder 9)